<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' standalone='yes' ?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/assets/bjoc/rss.css' type='text/css'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:dc='http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/'>
<channel>
<link>https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc</link>
<language>en</language>
<title>Beilstein Journal of Organic Chemistry</title>
<description>Beilstein Journal of Organic Chemistry</description>
<dc:creator>Beilstein Journal of Organic Chemistry - Syndicated Feeds</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-02-23T 1:52:52+00:00</dc:date>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 01:52:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>180</ttl>
<skipDays>
  <day>Saturday</day>
  <day>Sunday</day>
</skipDays>

<item>
<title>A new and efficient methodology for olefin epoxidation catalyzed by supported cobalt nanoparticles</title>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 09:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:identifier>1860-5397-17-46</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Beilstein Journal of Organic Chemistry 2021 17:46</dc:source>
<author>Luc&#237;a Rossi-Fern&#225;ndez, Viviana Dorn and Gabriel Radivoy</author>
<dc:subject>alkenes</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>cobalt nanoparticles</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>epoxides</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>oxidation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>TBHP</dc:subject>
<guid isPermaLink='false'>1860-5397-17-46</guid>
<link>https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/articles/17/46</link>
<dc:type>Full Research Paper</dc:type>
<category>Full Research Paper</category>
<enclosure type='application/pdf' url='https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/content/pdf/1860-5397-17-46.pdf'/>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p><font size='+1'><b>Abstract</b></font></p>
<p>A new heterogeneous catalytic system consisting of cobalt nanoparticles (CoNPs) supported on MgO and <i>tert</i>-butyl hydroperoxide (TBHP) as oxidant is presented. This CoNPs@MgO/<i>t</i>-BuOOH catalytic combination allowed the epoxidation of a variety of olefins with good to excellent yield and high selectivity. The catalyst preparation is simple and straightforward from commercially available starting materials and it could be recovered and reused maintaining its unaltered high activity.</p>
<p align='center'><img src='https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/content/figures/1860-5397-17-46-graphical-abstract.png?max-width=550' border='0'/></p>
<p><i>Beilstein J. Org. Chem.</i> <b>2021,</b> <i>17,</i> 519&#8211;526.&#160;doi:10.3762/bjoc.17.46</p>
]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Synthesis and physicochemical evaluation of fluorinated lipopeptide precursors of ligands for microbubble targeting</title>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 11:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:identifier>1860-5397-17-45</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Beilstein Journal of Organic Chemistry 2021 17:45</dc:source>
<author>Masayori Hagimori, Estefan&#237;a E. Mendoza-Ortega and Marie Pierre Krafft</author>
<dc:subject>adsorption at fluid interfaces</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>drug delivery</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>microbubble targeting</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>molecular imaging</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>monolayer</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>perfluoroalkylated lipopeptide</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>solid-phase peptide synthesis</dc:subject>
<guid isPermaLink='false'>1860-5397-17-45</guid>
<link>https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/articles/17/45</link>
<dc:type>Full Research Paper</dc:type>
<category>Full Research Paper</category>
<enclosure type='application/pdf' url='https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/content/pdf/1860-5397-17-45.pdf'/>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p><font size='+1'><b>Abstract</b></font></p>
<p>Ligand-targeted microbubbles are focusing interest for molecular imaging and delivery of chemotherapeutics. Lipid&#8211;peptide conjugates (lipopeptides) that feature alternating serine&#8211;glycine (SG)<i><sub>n</sub></i> segments rather than classical poly(oxyethylene) linkers between the lipid polar head and a targeting ligand were proposed for the liposome-mediated, selective delivery of anticancer drugs. Here, we report the synthesis of perfluoroalkylated lipopeptides (<i>F</i>-lipopeptides) bearing two hydrophobic chains (C<i><sub>n</sub></i>F<sub>2</sub><i><sub>n</sub></i><sub>+1</sub>, <i>n</i> = 6, 7, 8, <b>1</b>&#8211;<b>3</b>) grafted through a lysine moiety on a hydrophilic chain composed of a lysine&#8211;serine&#8211;serine (KSS) sequence followed by 5 SG sequences. These <i>F</i>-lipopeptides are precursors of targeting lipopeptide conjugates. A hydrocarbon counterpart with a C<sub>10</sub>H<sub>21</sub> chain (<b>4</b>) was synthesized for comparison. The capacity for the <i>F</i>-lipopeptides to spontaneously adsorb at the air/water interface and form monolayers when combined with dipalmitoylphosphatidylcholine (DPPC) was investigated. The <i>F</i>-lipopeptides <b>1</b>&#8211;<b>3</b> demonstrated a markedly enhanced tendency to form monolayers at the air/water interface, with equilibrium surface pressures reaching &#8776;7&#8211;10 mN m<sup>&#8722;1</sup> versus less than 1 mN m<sup>&#8722;1</sup> only for their hydrocarbon analog <b>4</b>. The <i>F</i>-lipopeptides penetrate in the DPPC monolayers in both liquid expanded (LE) and liquid condensed (LC) phases without interfacial film destabilization. By contrast, <b>4</b> provokes delipidation of the interfacial film. The incorporation of the <i>F</i>-lipopeptides <b>1</b>&#8211;<b>3</b> in microbubbles with a shell of DPPC and dipalmitoylphosphatidylethanolamine-PEG2000 decreased their mean diameter and increased their stability, the best results being obtained for the C<sub>8</sub>F<sub>17</sub>-bearing lipopeptide <b>3</b>. By contrast, the hydrocarbon lipopeptide led to microbubbles with a larger mean diameter and a significantly lower stability.</p>
<p align='center'><img src='https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/content/figures/1860-5397-17-45-graphical-abstract.png?max-width=550' border='0'/></p>
<p><i>Beilstein J. Org. Chem.</i> <b>2021,</b> <i>17,</i> 511&#8211;518.&#160;doi:10.3762/bjoc.17.45</p>
]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Synthesis of N-perfluoroalkyl-3,4-disubstituted pyrroles by rhodium-catalyzed transannulation of N-fluoroalkyl-1,2,3-triazoles with terminal alkynes</title>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 16:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:identifier>1860-5397-17-44</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Beilstein Journal of Organic Chemistry 2021 17:44</dc:source>
<author>Olga Bakhanovich, Viktor Khutorianskyi, Vladimir Motornov and Petr Beier</author>
<dc:subject>pyrrole</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>transannulation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>rhodium carbene</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>triazole</dc:subject>
<guid isPermaLink='false'>1860-5397-17-44</guid>
<link>https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/articles/17/44</link>
<dc:type>Full Research Paper</dc:type>
<category>Full Research Paper</category>
<enclosure type='application/pdf' url='https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/content/pdf/1860-5397-17-44.pdf'/>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p><font size='+1'><b>Abstract</b></font></p>
<p>The rhodium-catalyzed transannulation of <i>N-</i>perfluoroalkyl-1,2,3-triazoles with aromatic and aliphatic terminal alkynes under microwave heating conditions afforded <i>N-</i>perfluoroalkyl-3,4-disubstituted pyrroles (major products) and <i>N-</i>fluoroalkyl-2,4-disubstituted pyrroles (minor products). The observed selectivities in the case of the reactions with aliphatic alkynes were high.</p>
<p align='center'><img src='https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/content/figures/1860-5397-17-44-graphical-abstract.png?max-width=550' border='0'/></p>
<p><i>Beilstein J. Org. Chem.</i> <b>2021,</b> <i>17,</i> 504&#8211;510.&#160;doi:10.3762/bjoc.17.44</p>
]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>The synthesis of chiral &#946;-naphthyl-&#946;-sulfanyl ketones via enantioselective sulfa-Michael reaction in the presence of a bifunctional cinchona/sulfonamide organocatalyst</title>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 10:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:identifier>1860-5397-17-43</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Beilstein Journal of Organic Chemistry 2021 17:43</dc:source>
<author>Deniz T&#246;zendemir and Cihangir Tanyeli</author>
<dc:subject>asymmetric synthesis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>bifunctional catalysis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>cinchona alkaloids</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>organocatalysis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>sulfa-Michael reaction</dc:subject>
<guid isPermaLink='false'>1860-5397-17-43</guid>
<link>https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/articles/17/43</link>
<dc:type>Full Research Paper</dc:type>
<category>Full Research Paper</category>
<enclosure type='application/pdf' url='https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/content/pdf/1860-5397-17-43.pdf'/>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p><font size='+1'><b>Abstract</b></font></p>
<p>Cinchona alkaloid-derived organocatalysts are widely employed in various asymmetric transformations, yielding products with high enantiopurity. In this respect, a bifunctional quinine-derived sulfonamide organocatalyst was developed to catalyze the asymmetric sulfa-Michael reaction of naphthalene-1-thiol with <i>trans</i>-chalcone derivatives. The target sulfa-Michael adducts were obtained with up to 96% ee under mild conditions and with a low (1 mol %) catalyst loading. Selected enantiomerically enriched sulfa-Michael addition products were subjected to oxidation to obtain the corresponding sulfones.</p>
<p align='center'><img src='https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/content/figures/1860-5397-17-43-graphical-abstract.png?max-width=550' border='0'/></p>
<p><i>Beilstein J. Org. Chem.</i> <b>2021,</b> <i>17,</i> 494&#8211;503.&#160;doi:10.3762/bjoc.17.43</p>
]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Deoxygenative C2-heteroarylation of quinoline N-oxides: facile access to &#945;-triazolylquinolines</title>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 12:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:identifier>1860-5397-17-42</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Beilstein Journal of Organic Chemistry 2021 17:42</dc:source>
<author>Geetanjali S. Sontakke, Rahul K. Shukla and Chandra M. R. Volla</author>
<dc:subject>amination</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>heteroarylation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>quinoline N-oxides</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>regioselective</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>triazoles</dc:subject>
<guid isPermaLink='false'>1860-5397-17-42</guid>
<link>https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/articles/17/42</link>
<dc:type>Letter</dc:type>
<category>Letter</category>
<enclosure type='application/pdf' url='https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/content/pdf/1860-5397-17-42.pdf'/>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p><font size='+1'><b>Abstract</b></font></p>
<p>A metal- and additive-free, highly efficient, step-economical deoxygenative C2-heteroarylation of quinolines and isoquinolines was achieved from readily available <i>N</i>-oxides and <i>N</i>-sulfonyl-1,2,3-triazoles. A variety of &#945;-triazolylquinoline derivatives were synthesized with good regioselectivity and in excellent yields under mild reaction conditions. Further, a gram-scale and one-pot synthesis illustrated the efficacy and simplicity of the developed protocol. The current transformation was also found to be compatible for the late-stage modification of natural products.</p>
<p align='center'><img src='https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/content/figures/1860-5397-17-42-graphical-abstract.png?max-width=550' border='0'/></p>
<p><i>Beilstein J. Org. Chem.</i> <b>2021,</b> <i>17,</i> 485&#8211;493.&#160;doi:10.3762/bjoc.17.42</p>
]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Synthetic strategies of phosphonodepsipeptides</title>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 10:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:identifier>1860-5397-17-41</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Beilstein Journal of Organic Chemistry 2021 17:41</dc:source>
<author>Jiaxi Xu</author>
<dc:subject>alkylation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>mimetic</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>multicomponent condensation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>peptide</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>phosphonopeptide</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>phosphonodepsipeptide</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>phosphonylation</dc:subject>
<guid isPermaLink='false'>1860-5397-17-41</guid>
<link>https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/articles/17/41</link>
<dc:type>Review</dc:type>
<category>Review</category>
<enclosure type='application/pdf' url='https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/content/pdf/1860-5397-17-41.pdf'/>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p><font size='+1'><b>Abstract</b></font></p>
<p>Phosphonodepsipeptides are phosphorus analogues of depsipeptides and phosphonate-linked analogues of naturally occurring peptides. They are more stable than phosphonopeptides and have been widely applied as enzyme inhibitors, haptens for the production of antibodies, biological agents, and prodrugs. The synthetic strategies towards phosphonodepsipeptides are reviewed, including the phosphonylation of hydroxy esters with phosphonochloridates, the condensation of phosphonic monoesters and hydroxy esters, the alkylation of phosphonic monoesters with 1-(alkoxycarbonyl)alkyl halides or sulfonates, multicomponent condensation of amides, aldehydes, and dichlorophosphites followed by alcoholysis with hydroxy esters, the phosphinylation of hydroxy esters with phosphonochloridites followed by oxidation, and the carbene insertion of <i>N</i>-protected amino acids with 1-diazoalkylphosphonates. This review includes the synthesis of &#945;-, &#946;-, and &#947;-phosphonodepsipeptides and phosphonodepsipeptides with C-1-hydroxyalkylphosphonic acids.</p>
<p align='center'><img src='https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/content/figures/1860-5397-17-41-graphical-abstract.png?max-width=550' border='0'/></p>
<p><i>Beilstein J. Org. Chem.</i> <b>2021,</b> <i>17,</i> 461&#8211;484.&#160;doi:10.3762/bjoc.17.41</p>
]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Biochemistry of fluoroprolines: the prospect of making fluorine a bioelement</title>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 11:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:identifier>1860-5397-17-40</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Beilstein Journal of Organic Chemistry 2021 17:40</dc:source>
<author>Vladimir Kubyshkin, Rebecca Davis and Nediljko Budisa</author>
<dc:subject>amino acids</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>evolution</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>fluorine</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>proline</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>proteins</dc:subject>
<guid isPermaLink='false'>1860-5397-17-40</guid>
<link>https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/articles/17/40</link>
<dc:type>Review</dc:type>
<category>Review</category>
<enclosure type='application/pdf' url='https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/content/pdf/1860-5397-17-40.pdf'/>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p><font size='+1'><b>Abstract</b></font></p>
<p>Due to the heterocyclic structure and distinct conformational profile, proline is unique in the repertoire of the 20 amino acids coded into proteins. Here, we summarize the biochemical work on the replacement of proline with (4<i>R</i>)- and (4<i>S</i>)-fluoroproline as well as 4,4-difluoroproline in proteins done mainly in the last two decades. We first recapitulate the complex position and biochemical fate of proline in the biochemistry of a cell, discuss the physicochemical properties of fluoroprolines, and overview the attempts to use these amino acids as proline replacements in studies of protein production and folding. Fluorinated proline replacements are able to elevate the protein expression speed and yields and improve the thermodynamic and kinetic folding profiles of individual proteins. In this context, fluoroprolines can be viewed as useful tools in the biotechnological toolbox. As a prospect, we envision that proteome-wide proline-to-fluoroproline substitutions could be possible. We suggest a hypothetical scenario for the use of laboratory evolutionary methods with fluoroprolines as a suitable vehicle to introduce fluorine into living cells. This approach may enable creation of synthetic cells endowed with artificial biodiversity, containing fluorine as a bioelement.</p>
<p align='center'><img src='https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/content/figures/1860-5397-17-40-graphical-abstract.png?max-width=550' border='0'/></p>
<p><i>Beilstein J. Org. Chem.</i> <b>2021,</b> <i>17,</i> 439&#8211;460.&#160;doi:10.3762/bjoc.17.40</p>
]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Synthesis of trifluoromethyl ketones by nucleophilic trifluoromethylation of esters under a fluoroform/KHMDS/triglyme system</title>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 09:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:identifier>1860-5397-17-39</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Beilstein Journal of Organic Chemistry 2021 17:39</dc:source>
<author>Yamato Fujihira, Yumeng Liang, Makoto Ono, Kazuki Hirano, Takumi Kagawa and Norio Shibata</author>
<dc:subject>fluoroform</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>greenhouse gas</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>HFC-23</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>trifluoromethyl ketones</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>trifluoromethylation</dc:subject>
<guid isPermaLink='false'>1860-5397-17-39</guid>
<link>https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/articles/17/39</link>
<dc:type>Letter</dc:type>
<category>Letter</category>
<enclosure type='application/pdf' url='https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/content/pdf/1860-5397-17-39.pdf'/>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p><font size='+1'><b>Abstract</b></font></p>
<p>A straightforward method that enables the formation of biologically attractive trifluoromethyl ketones from readily available methyl esters using the potent greenhouse gas fluoroform (HCF<sub>3</sub>, HFC-23) was developed. The combination of fluoroform and KHMDS in triglyme at &#8722;40 &#176;C was effective for this transformation, with good yields as high as 92%. Substrate scope of the trifluoromethylation procedure was explored for aromatic, aliphatic, and conjugated methyl esters. This study presents a straightforward trifluoromethylation process of various methyl esters that convert well to the corresponding trifluoromethyl ketones. The tolerance of various pharmacophores under the reaction conditions was also explored.</p>
<p align='center'><img src='https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/content/figures/1860-5397-17-39-graphical-abstract.png?max-width=550' border='0'/></p>
<p><i>Beilstein J. Org. Chem.</i> <b>2021,</b> <i>17,</i> 431&#8211;438.&#160;doi:10.3762/bjoc.17.39</p>
]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Identification of volatiles from six marine Celeribacter strains</title>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 15:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:identifier>1860-5397-17-38</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Beilstein Journal of Organic Chemistry 2021 17:38</dc:source>
<author>Anuj Kumar Chhalodia, Jan Rinkel, Dorota Konvalinkova, J&#246;rn Petersen and Jeroen S. Dickschat</author>
<dc:subject>GC&#8211;MS</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>isotopes</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Roseobacter</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>sulfur metabolism</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>volatiles</dc:subject>
<guid isPermaLink='false'>1860-5397-17-38</guid>
<link>https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/articles/17/38</link>
<dc:type>Full Research Paper</dc:type>
<category>Full Research Paper</category>
<enclosure type='application/pdf' url='https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/content/pdf/1860-5397-17-38.pdf'/>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p><font size='+1'><b>Abstract</b></font></p>
<p>The volatiles emitted from six marine <i>Rhodobacteraceae</i> species of the genus <i>Celeribacter</i> were investigated by GC&#8211;MS. Besides several known compounds including dimethyl trisulfide and <i>S</i>-methyl methanethiosulfonate, the sulfur-containing compounds ethyl (<i>E</i>)-3-(methylsulfanyl)acrylate and 2-(methyldisulfanyl)benzothiazole were identified and their structures were verified by synthesis. Feeding experiments with [<i>methyl</i>-<sup>2</sup>H<sub>3</sub>]methionine, [<i>methyl</i>-<sup>13</sup>C]methionine and [<sup>34</sup>S]-3-(dimethylsulfonio)propanoate (DMSP) resulted in the high incorporation into dimethyl trisulfide and <i>S</i>-methyl methanethiosulfonate, and revealed the origin of the methylsulfanyl group of 2-(methyldisulfanyl)benzothiazole from methionine or DMSP, while the biosynthetic origin of the benzothiazol-2-ylsulfanyl portion could not be traced. The heterocyclic moiety of this compound is likely of anthropogenic origin, because 2-mercaptobenzothiazole is used in the sulfur vulcanization of rubber. Also in none of the feeding experiments incorporation into ethyl (<i>E</i>)-3-(methylsulfanyl)acrylate could be observed, questioning its bacterial origin. Our results demonstrate that the <i>Celeribacter</i> strains are capable of methionine and DMSP degradation to widespread sulfur volatiles, but the analysis of trace compounds in natural samples must be taken with care.</p>
<p align='center'><img src='https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/content/figures/1860-5397-17-38-graphical-abstract.png?max-width=550' border='0'/></p>
<p><i>Beilstein J. Org. Chem.</i> <b>2021,</b> <i>17,</i> 420&#8211;430.&#160;doi:10.3762/bjoc.17.38</p>
]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>1,2,3-Triazoles as leaving groups: SNAr reactions of 2,6-bistriazolylpurines with O- and C-nucleophiles</title>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 10:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:identifier>1860-5397-17-37</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Beilstein Journal of Organic Chemistry 2021 17:37</dc:source>
<author>Dace C&#299;rule, Irina Novosjolova, &#274;rika Bizd&#275;na and M&#257;ris Turks</author>
<dc:subject>2,6-bistriazolyl purines</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>nucleophilic aromatic substitution</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>purine nucleosides</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>triazoles</dc:subject>
<guid isPermaLink='false'>1860-5397-17-37</guid>
<link>https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/articles/17/37</link>
<dc:type>Full Research Paper</dc:type>
<category>Full Research Paper</category>
<enclosure type='application/pdf' url='https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/content/pdf/1860-5397-17-37.pdf'/>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p><font size='+1'><b>Abstract</b></font></p>
<p>A new approach was designed for the synthesis of C6-substituted 2-triazolylpurine derivatives. A series of substituted products was obtained in S<sub>N</sub>Ar reactions between 2,6-bistriazolylpurine derivatives and O- and C-nucleophiles under mild conditions. The products were isolated in yields up to 87%. The developed C&#8211;O and C&#8211;C bond forming reactions clearly show the ability of the 1,2,3-triazolyl ring at the C6 position of purine to act as leaving group.</p>
<p align='center'><img src='https://www.beilstein-journals.org/bjoc/content/figures/1860-5397-17-37-graphical-abstract.png?max-width=550' border='0'/></p>
<p><i>Beilstein J. Org. Chem.</i> <b>2021,</b> <i>17,</i> 410&#8211;419.&#160;doi:10.3762/bjoc.17.37</p>
]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
