<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>PLOS ONE</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/" />
  <author>
    <name>PLOS</name>
    <uri>https://journals.plos.org/plosone/</uri>
    <email>webmaster@plos.org</email>
  </author>
  <subtitle type="text">accelerating the publication of peer-reviewed science</subtitle>
  <id>http://journals.plos.org/plosone/feed/atom</id>
  <rights>All PLOS articles are Open Access.</rights>
  <icon>https://journals.plos.org/plosone/resource/img/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://journals.plos.org/plosone/resource/img/favicon.ico</logo>
  <updated>2021-02-27T02:24:50Z</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>Correction: Seed germination ecology of &lt;i&gt;Conyza stricta&lt;/i&gt; Willd. and implications for management</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0248083" title="Correction: Seed germination ecology of &lt;i&gt;Conyza stricta&lt;/i&gt; Willd. and implications for management" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0248083.PDF" title="(PDF) Correction: Seed germination ecology of &lt;i&gt;Conyza stricta&lt;/i&gt; Willd. and implications for management" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0248083.XML" title="(XML) Correction: Seed germination ecology of &lt;i&gt;Conyza stricta&lt;/i&gt; Willd. and implications for management" />
    <author>
      <name>Safdar Ali</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Fakhar Din Khan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rehmat Ullah</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rahmat Ullah Shah</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Saud Alamri</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Maeesh AlHarthi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Manzer H. Siddiqui</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0248083</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Safdar Ali, Fakhar Din Khan, Rehmat Ullah, Rahmat Ullah Shah, Saud Alamri, Maeesh AlHarthi, Manzer H. Siddiqui&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Correction: The intra-articular administration of triamcinolone hexacetonide in the treatment of osteoarthritis. Its effects in a naturally occurring canine osteoarthritis model</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0248082" title="Correction: The intra-articular administration of triamcinolone hexacetonide in the treatment of osteoarthritis. Its effects in a naturally occurring canine osteoarthritis model" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0248082.PDF" title="(PDF) Correction: The intra-articular administration of triamcinolone hexacetonide in the treatment of osteoarthritis. Its effects in a naturally occurring canine osteoarthritis model" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0248082.XML" title="(XML) Correction: The intra-articular administration of triamcinolone hexacetonide in the treatment of osteoarthritis. Its effects in a naturally occurring canine osteoarthritis model" />
    <author>
      <name>João C. Alves</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ana Santos</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Patrícia Jorge</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Catarina Lavrador</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>L. Miguel Carreira</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0248082</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by João C. Alves, Ana Santos, Patrícia Jorge, Catarina Lavrador, L. Miguel Carreira&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Correction: Social isolation in rats: Effects on animal welfare and molecular markers for neuroplasticity</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0248070" title="Correction: Social isolation in rats: Effects on animal welfare and molecular markers for neuroplasticity" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0248070.PDF" title="(PDF) Correction: Social isolation in rats: Effects on animal welfare and molecular markers for neuroplasticity" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0248070.XML" title="(XML) Correction: Social isolation in rats: Effects on animal welfare and molecular markers for neuroplasticity" />
    <author>
      <name>Veronica Begni</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alice Sanson</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Natascha Pfeiffer</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Christiane Brandwein</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dragos Inta</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Steven R. Talbot</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marco Andrea Riva</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Peter Gass</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Anne Stephanie Mallien</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0248070</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Veronica Begni, Alice Sanson, Natascha Pfeiffer, Christiane Brandwein, Dragos Inta, Steven R. Talbot, Marco Andrea Riva, Peter Gass, Anne Stephanie Mallien&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on the lifestyle, mental health, and quality of life of adults in South Korea</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247970" title="Impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on the lifestyle, mental health, and quality of life of adults in South Korea" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247970.PDF" title="(PDF) Impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on the lifestyle, mental health, and quality of life of adults in South Korea" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247970.XML" title="(XML) Impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on the lifestyle, mental health, and quality of life of adults in South Korea" />
    <author>
      <name>Kang-Hyun Park</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ah-Ram Kim</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Min-Ah Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Seung-Ju Lim</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ji-Hyuk Park</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247970</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Kang-Hyun Park, Ah-Ram Kim, Min-Ah Yang, Seung-Ju Lim, Ji-Hyuk Park&lt;/p&gt;
Objective &lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic continues to pose significant challenges to nations. The Korean government aimed to mitigate the spread of COVID-19 through stay-at-home strategies and maintaining social distance, which are likely to result in major changes in the lifestyle, mental health, and quality of life of citizens. This study aimed to investigate the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on these factors in Koreans over 20 years old.&lt;/p&gt; Methods &lt;p&gt;The study sample consisted of 104 adults in South Korea aged over 20 years. An online survey was conducted between August and October 2020, in which participants were asked to complete the Yonsei Lifestyle Profile to assess lifestyle changes, the Center for Epidemiological Studies-Depression Scale, and the World Health Organization Quality of Life Scale abbreviated version. To investigate the changes in people’s lifestyles, depression, and quality of life post COVID-19, descriptive statistics were calculated for these indicators before and after the onset of the pandemic. The p-value was two-sided, and values &lt;0.05, were regarded as statistically significant.&lt;/p&gt; Results &lt;p&gt;There was a significant decline in physical and other meaningful activities, including activities of daily living, leisure, social activity, and education. However, there were no significant changes in nutrition, except in the consumption of carbohydrates and minerals. Participants reported that their quality of life and mental health had decreased after the pandemic struck.&lt;/p&gt; Conclusions &lt;p&gt;We obtained novel data on the changes in the lifestyle, mental health, and quality of life of South Korean adults before and after the onset of the pandemic. The results of our study may assist health policymakers and practitioners in the development of health education or relevant interventions to deal with the pandemic situation as well as future crises.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Temperature-induced microstructural changes in shells of laboratory-grown &lt;i&gt;Arctica islandica&lt;/i&gt; (Bivalvia)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247968" title="Temperature-induced microstructural changes in shells of laboratory-grown &lt;i&gt;Arctica islandica&lt;/i&gt; (Bivalvia)" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247968.PDF" title="(PDF) Temperature-induced microstructural changes in shells of laboratory-grown &lt;i&gt;Arctica islandica&lt;/i&gt; (Bivalvia)" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247968.XML" title="(XML) Temperature-induced microstructural changes in shells of laboratory-grown &lt;i&gt;Arctica islandica&lt;/i&gt; (Bivalvia)" />
    <author>
      <name>Nils Höche</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eric O. Walliser</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Niels J. de Winter</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rob Witbaard</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bernd R. Schöne</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247968</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Nils Höche, Eric O. Walliser, Niels J. de Winter, Rob Witbaard, Bernd R. Schöne&lt;/p&gt;

Bivalve shells are increasingly used as archives for high-resolution paleoclimate analyses. However, there is still an urgent need for quantitative temperature proxies that work without knowledge of the water chemistry–as is required for δ&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;O-based paleothermometry–and can better withstand diagenetic overprint. Recently, microstructural properties have been identified as a potential candidate fulfilling these requirements. So far, only few different microstructure categories (nacreous, prismatic and crossed-lamellar) of some short-lived species have been studied in detail, and in all such studies, the size and/or shape of individual biomineral units was found to increase with water temperature. Here, we explore whether the same applies to properties of the crossed-acicular microstructure in the hinge plate of &lt;i&gt;Arctica islandica&lt;/i&gt;, the microstructurally most uniform shell portion in this species. In order to focus solely on the effect of temperature on microstructural properties, this study uses bivalves that grew their shells under controlled temperature conditions (1, 3, 6, 9, 12 and 15°C) in the laboratory. With increasing temperature, the size of the largest individual biomineral units and the relative proportion of shell occupied by the crystalline phase increased. The size of the largest pores, a specific microstructural feature of &lt;i&gt;A&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;i&gt;islandica&lt;/i&gt;, whose potential role in biomineralization is discussed here, increased exponentially with culturing temperature. This study employs scanning electron microscopy in combination with automated image processing software, including an innovative machine learning–based image segmentation method. The new method greatly facilitates the recognition of microstructural entities and enables a faster and more reliable microstructural analysis than previously used techniques. Results of this study establish the new microstructural temperature proxy in the crossed-acicular microstructures of &lt;i&gt;A&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;i&gt;islandica&lt;/i&gt; and point to an overarching control mechanism of temperature on the micrometer-scale architecture of bivalve shells across species boundaries.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Age, disability, and household composition of nurses and physicians who are not in the labor force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247967" title="Age, disability, and household composition of nurses and physicians who are not in the labor force" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247967.PDF" title="(PDF) Age, disability, and household composition of nurses and physicians who are not in the labor force" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247967.XML" title="(XML) Age, disability, and household composition of nurses and physicians who are not in the labor force" />
    <author>
      <name>Dan P. Ly</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247967</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Dan P. Ly&lt;/p&gt;

While several areas in the United States have asked nurses and physicians who are not in the labor force to return to help with the COVID-19 pandemic, little is known about the characteristics of these clinicians that may present barriers to returning. We studied age, disability, and household composition of clinicians not in the workforce using the American Community Survey from 2014 to 2018, a nationally-representative survey of US households administered by the US Census. Overall, we found that, for nurses and physicians not in the labor force, over three-quarters were 55 and over and about 15 percent had a disability. For female nurses and physicians not in the labor force, over half of those ages 20–54 had a child under 15 at home and over half of those ages 65+ had another adult 65 and over at home. These characteristics may present challenges and risks to returning.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Understanding the impact of the SARS-COV-2 pandemic on hospitalized patients with substance use disorder</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247951" title="Understanding the impact of the SARS-COV-2 pandemic on hospitalized patients with substance use disorder" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247951.PDF" title="(PDF) Understanding the impact of the SARS-COV-2 pandemic on hospitalized patients with substance use disorder" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247951.XML" title="(XML) Understanding the impact of the SARS-COV-2 pandemic on hospitalized patients with substance use disorder" />
    <author>
      <name>Caroline King</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Vega</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dana Button</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Nicolaidis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jessica Gregg</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Honora Englander</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247951</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Caroline King, Taylor Vega, Dana Button, Christina Nicolaidis, Jessica Gregg, Honora Englander&lt;/p&gt;
Background &lt;p&gt;The SARS-COV-2 pandemic rapidly shifted dynamics around hospitalization for many communities. This study aimed to evaluate how the pandemic altered the experience of healthcare, acute illness, and care transitions among hospitalized patients with substance use disorder (SUD).&lt;/p&gt; Methods &lt;p&gt;We performed a qualitative study at an academic medical center in Portland, Oregon, in Spring 2020. We conducted semi-structured interviews, and conducted a thematic analysis, using an inductive approach, at a semantic level.&lt;/p&gt; Results &lt;p&gt;We enrolled 27 participants, and identified four main themes: 1) shuttered community resources threatened patients’ basic survival adaptations; 2) changes in outpatient care increased reliance on hospitals as safety nets; 3) hospital policy changes made staying in the hospital harder than usual; and, 4) care transitions out of the hospital were highly uncertain.&lt;/p&gt; Discussion &lt;p&gt;Hospitalized adults with SUD were further marginalized during the SARS-COV-2 pandemic. Systems must address the needs of marginalized patients in future disruptive events.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cardiac-specific troponins in uncomplicated pregnancy and pre-eclampsia: A systematic review</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247946" title="Cardiac-specific troponins in uncomplicated pregnancy and pre-eclampsia: A systematic review" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247946.PDF" title="(PDF) Cardiac-specific troponins in uncomplicated pregnancy and pre-eclampsia: A systematic review" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247946.XML" title="(XML) Cardiac-specific troponins in uncomplicated pregnancy and pre-eclampsia: A systematic review" />
    <author>
      <name>Samuel Dockree</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Brook</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Brian Shine</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tim James</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lauren Green</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Manu Vatish</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247946</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Samuel Dockree, Jennifer Brook, Brian Shine, Tim James, Lauren Green, Manu Vatish&lt;/p&gt;
Background &lt;p&gt;The risk of myocardial infarction (MI) increases during pregnancy, particularly in women with pre-eclampsia. MI is diagnosed by measuring high blood levels of cardiac-specific troponin (cTn), although this may be elevated in women with pre-eclampsia without MI, which increases diagnostic uncertainty. It is unclear how much cTn is elevated in uncomplicated and complicated pregnancy, which may affect whether the existing reference intervals can be used in pregnant women. Previous reviews have not investigated high-sensitivity troponin in pregnancy, compared to older, less sensitive methods.&lt;/p&gt; Methods &lt;p&gt;Electronic searches using the terms “troponin I” or “troponin T”, and “pregnancy”, “pregnancy complications” or “obstetrics”. cTn levels were extracted from studies of women with uncomplicated pregnancies or pre-eclampsia.&lt;/p&gt; Results &lt;p&gt;The search identified ten studies with 1581 women. Eight studies used contemporary methods that may be too insensitive to use reliably in this clinical setting. Two studies used high-sensitivity assays, with one reporting an elevation in troponin I (TnI) in pre-eclampsia compared to uncomplicated pregnancy, and the other only examining women with pre-eclampsia.Seven studies compared cTn between women with pre-eclampsia or uncomplicated pregnancy using any assay. Seven studies showed elevated TnI in pre-eclampsia compared to uncomplicated pregnancy or non-pregnant women. One study measured troponin T (TnT) in pregnancy but did not examine pre-eclampsia.&lt;/p&gt; Conclusion &lt;p&gt;TnI appears to be elevated in pre-eclampsia, irrespective of methodology, which may reflect the role of cardiac stress in this condition. TnI may be similar in healthy pregnant and non-pregnant women, but we found no literature reporting pregnancy-specific reference intervals using high-sensitivity tests. This limits broader application of cTn in pregnancy. There is a need to define reference intervals for cTn in pregnant women, which should involve serial sampling throughout pregnancy, with careful consideration for gestational age and body mass index, which cause dynamic changes in normal maternal physiology.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Protein intake in inhabitants with regular exercise is associated with sleep quality: Results of the Shika study</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247926" title="Protein intake in inhabitants with regular exercise is associated with sleep quality: Results of the Shika study" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247926.PDF" title="(PDF) Protein intake in inhabitants with regular exercise is associated with sleep quality: Results of the Shika study" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247926.XML" title="(XML) Protein intake in inhabitants with regular exercise is associated with sleep quality: Results of the Shika study" />
    <author>
      <name>Fumihiko Suzuki</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Emi Morita</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sakae Miyagi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hiromasa Tsujiguchi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Akinori Hara</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Thao Thi Thu Nguyen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yukari Shimizu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Koichiro Hayashi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Keita Suzuki</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Takayuki Kannon</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Atsushi Tajima</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sumire Matsumoto</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Asuka Ishihara</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daisuke Hori</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shotaro Doki</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuichi Oi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shinichiro Sasahara</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Makoto Satoh</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ichiyo Matsuzaki</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Masashi Yanagisawa</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Toshiharu Ikaga</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hiroyuki Nakamura</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247926</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Fumihiko Suzuki, Emi Morita, Sakae Miyagi, Hiromasa Tsujiguchi, Akinori Hara, Thao Thi Thu Nguyen, Yukari Shimizu, Koichiro Hayashi, Keita Suzuki, Takayuki Kannon, Atsushi Tajima, Sumire Matsumoto, Asuka Ishihara, Daisuke Hori, Shotaro Doki, Yuichi Oi, Shinichiro Sasahara, Makoto Satoh, Ichiyo Matsuzaki, Masashi Yanagisawa, Toshiharu Ikaga, Hiroyuki Nakamura&lt;/p&gt;
Study objectives &lt;p&gt;Although associations between sleep quality and environmental factors and nutrient intake have been reported, interactions between these factors have not been elucidated in detail. Therefore, this cross-sectional study examined the effects of regular exercise and nutrient intake on sleep quality using the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (PSQI), which is the most frequently used index for sleep evaluation.&lt;/p&gt; Methods &lt;p&gt;The participants included 378 individuals aged 40 years or older living in Shika Town, Ishikawa Prefecture. Of these individuals, 185 met the inclusion criteria. The participants completed a self-administered questionnaire assessing lifestyle habits and frequency and duration of exercise, the PSQI, and the brief-type self-administered diet history questionnaire (BDHQ) on nutrient intake.&lt;/p&gt; Results &lt;p&gt;A two-way analysis of covariance on regular exercise and PSQI scores indicated that protein intake (17.13% of energy) was significantly higher in the regular exercise and PSQI ≤10 groups than in the non-regular exercise or PSQI ≥11 groups (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0.002). In a multiple logistic regression analysis with PSQI scores (≤10 and ≥11), protein intake was a significant independent variable in any of the models adjusted for confounding factors such as age, sex, body mass index, current smoker, and current drinker (OR: 1.357, 95% CI: 1.081, 1.704, &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0.009) in the regular exercise group but not in the non-regular exercise group.ConclusionsWe identified a positive relationship between sleep quality and protein intake in the regular exercise group. These findings suggest that regular exercise at least twice a week for 30 minutes or longer combined with high protein intake contributes to good sleep quality.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Health system and quality of care factors contributing to maternal deaths in East Java, Indonesia</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247911" title="Health system and quality of care factors contributing to maternal deaths in East Java, Indonesia" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247911.PDF" title="(PDF) Health system and quality of care factors contributing to maternal deaths in East Java, Indonesia" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247911.XML" title="(XML) Health system and quality of care factors contributing to maternal deaths in East Java, Indonesia" />
    <author>
      <name>Mohammad Afzal Mahmood</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hendy Hendarto</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Muhammad Ardian Cahya Laksana</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hanifa Erlin Damayanti</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mohammad Hud Suhargono</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rizki Pranadyan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kohar Hari Santoso</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kartika Sri Redjeki</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Baksono Winard</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Budi Prasetyo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jorien Vercruyssen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>John Robert Moss</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Peng Bi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Syarifah Masitah</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Warsiti</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Aldilia Wyasti Pratama</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Erni Rosita Dewi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Charity Hartika Listiyani</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ismi Mufidah</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247911</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Mohammad Afzal Mahmood, Hendy Hendarto, Muhammad Ardian Cahya Laksana, Hanifa Erlin Damayanti, Mohammad Hud Suhargono, Rizki Pranadyan, Kohar Hari Santoso, Kartika Sri Redjeki, Baksono Winard, Budi Prasetyo, Jorien Vercruyssen, John Robert Moss, Peng Bi, Syarifah Masitah, Warsiti, Aldilia Wyasti Pratama, Erni Rosita Dewi, Charity Hartika Listiyani, Ismi Mufidah&lt;/p&gt;

Despite most Indonesian women now receiving antenatal care on the nationally recommended four occasions and being delivered by skilled birth attendants, the nation’s maternal mortality ratio (MMR) is estimated as 177 per 100,000 live births. Recent research in a rural district of Indonesia has indicated that poor service quality due to organizational and personnel factors is now a major determinant of this high MMR. The present research is an in-depth analysis of possible health service organizational and quality of care related causes of death among 30 women admitted to a peak referral hospital in a major Indonesian city. Despite their condition being complex or deteriorating, most of these women arrived at the hospital in a state where it was feasible to prevent death with good quality care. Poor application of protocols, poor information flow from frontline hospitals to the peak referral hospital, delays in emergency care, and delays in management of deteriorating patients were the main contributing factors to these deaths. Pyramidal referrals also contributed, as many women were initially referred to hospitals where their condition could not be effectively managed. While generic quality improvement measures, particularly training and monitoring for rigorous application of clinical protocols (including forward planning for deteriorating patients) will help improve the situation, the districts and hospitals need to develop capacity to assess their local situation. Unless local organisational factors, staff knowledge and skill, blood and blood product availability, and local reasons for delays in providing care are identified, it may not be possible to effectively reduce the adverse pregnancy outcomes.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Serological evidence of avian HEV antibodies in apparently healthy chickens in southwest Nigeria</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247889" title="Serological evidence of avian HEV antibodies in apparently healthy chickens in southwest Nigeria" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247889.PDF" title="(PDF) Serological evidence of avian HEV antibodies in apparently healthy chickens in southwest Nigeria" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247889.XML" title="(XML) Serological evidence of avian HEV antibodies in apparently healthy chickens in southwest Nigeria" />
    <author>
      <name>Fisayo Temilade Osamudiamen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Olusola Aanuoluwapo Akanbi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Oladimeji Oluwayelu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>C. -Thomas Bock</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Patrycja Klink</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247889</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Fisayo Temilade Osamudiamen, Olusola Aanuoluwapo Akanbi, Daniel Oladimeji Oluwayelu, C. -Thomas Bock, Patrycja Klink&lt;/p&gt;

Avian hepatitis E virus (aHEV) is associated with hepatitis-splenomegaly syndrome, big liver and spleen disease and hepatic rupture haemorrhage syndrome. However, the knowledge about aHEV in commercial layer chickens in Nigeria is scarce. In this study, 460 serum samples obtained from 36 apparently healthy commercial layer chicken flocks in three states (Ogun, Osun and Oyo States) of southwestern Nigeria were analysed by enzyme linked immunosorbent assay for the presence of anti-aHEV immunoglobulin Y (IgY) antibodies. In total, the overall seroprevalence of anti-aHEV antibodies was 14.6%. The serological analysis revealed that 75% of the flocks examined were positive for anti-aHEV IgY antibodies from chickens of various ages in all three states. The percentage of the seropositive chickens in the three states varied from flock to flock ranging from 60% to 88.8% and seropositive chickens were detected at any age (24–52 weeks of age) without significant differences between the age groups. This is the first report assessing the presence of aHEV antibodies in chickens from Nigeria. The detection of anti-aHEV antibodies in commercial layer chickens in this study emphasizes the importance of serosurveillance in disease monitoring due to the economic threat posed by aHEV as a result of decreased egg production and increased mortality in affected commercial layer chicken farms. However, further studies are essential to reveal the clinical implications and to assess the real burden of aHEV in Nigeria.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>High prevalence of gastroschisis in Brazilian triple side border: A socioenvironmental spatial analysis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247863" title="High prevalence of gastroschisis in Brazilian triple side border: A socioenvironmental spatial analysis" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247863.PDF" title="(PDF) High prevalence of gastroschisis in Brazilian triple side border: A socioenvironmental spatial analysis" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247863.XML" title="(XML) High prevalence of gastroschisis in Brazilian triple side border: A socioenvironmental spatial analysis" />
    <author>
      <name>Suzana de Souza</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Oscar Kenji Nihei</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Cezar Rangel Pestana</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247863</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Suzana de Souza, Oscar Kenji Nihei, Cezar Rangel Pestana&lt;/p&gt;

This research investigated the spatial association between socioenvironmental factors and gastroschisis in Brazilian triple side border. A geographic analysis for gastroschisis prevalence was performed considering census sector units using Global Moran Index, Local Indicator of Spatial Association Analysis and Getis Ord statistics. Sociodemographic factors included rate of adolescent and parturients over 35 years; population with no income and above 5 minimum wages; rate of late prenatal; and proximity to power transmission lines. Logistic regression models were applied to verify the association between socio-environmental factors and prevalence of gastroschisis. No global spatial correlation was observed in the distribution of gastroschisis (Moran´s I = 0.006; p = 0.319). However, multiple logistic regression showed census sectors with positive cases had higher probability to power transmission lines proximity (OR 3,47; CI 95% 1,11–10,79; p = 0,031). Yet, spatial scan statistic showed low risk for gastroschisis in southern city region (OR = 0; p = 0.035) in opposite to power transmission lines location. The study design does not allow us to attest the causality between power transmission lines and gastroschisis but these findings support the potential exposure risk of pregnant to electromagnetic fields.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Impact of pneumococcal conjugate vaccine on invasive pneumococcal disease in children under 5 years of age in the Czech Republic</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247862" title="Impact of pneumococcal conjugate vaccine on invasive pneumococcal disease in children under 5 years of age in the Czech Republic" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247862.PDF" title="(PDF) Impact of pneumococcal conjugate vaccine on invasive pneumococcal disease in children under 5 years of age in the Czech Republic" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247862.XML" title="(XML) Impact of pneumococcal conjugate vaccine on invasive pneumococcal disease in children under 5 years of age in the Czech Republic" />
    <author>
      <name>Jana Kozakova</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pavla Krizova</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marek Maly</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247862</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Jana Kozakova, Pavla Krizova, Marek Maly&lt;/p&gt;
Introduction &lt;p&gt;The aim of this study is to analyse the impact of vaccination of infants with pneumococcal conjugate vaccine (PCV) on the incidence of invasive pneumococcal disease (IPD) in children under 5 years of age in the Czech Republic.&lt;/p&gt; Material and methods &lt;p&gt;The present study includes all IPD cases reported in children aged 0–4 years within the surveillance program in 2007–2017. The impact of PCV is analysed for five categories of IPD: cases caused by all serotypes, cases caused by PCV7 serotypes (4, 6B, 9V, 14, 18C, 19F, and 23F), cases caused by three additional PCV10 serotypes (1, 5, and 7F), cases caused by three additional PCV13 serotypes (3, 6A, and 19A), and cases caused by non-PCV serotypes. To assess the impact of PCV, the study period was divided into the pre-vaccination period 2007–2008 and post-vaccination period 2009–2017, which was divided into three three-year parts: 2009–2011, 2012–2014, and 2015–2017. Analysis of differences between periods was based on the Poisson regression model where the population numbers were handled as an offset.&lt;/p&gt; Results &lt;p&gt;The annual incidence of IPD in children under 5 years of age caused by all serotypes has had a downward trend since 2007: it dropped from 8.52/100 000 in 2007 to 2.67/100 000 in 2017, with slight increases in 2010 and 2013. All three post-vaccination periods show significantly lower (p&lt;0.001) incidences in comparison to the pre-vaccination period, but they do not statistically significantly differ from each other.&lt;/p&gt; Conclusions &lt;p&gt;IPD surveillance data in the Czech Republic show that after the introduction of PCV vaccination of infants, there has been a significant decrease in the IPD incidence of children under 5 years of age. Continued IPD surveillance is essential to monitor for possible post-vaccination serotype replacement.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ultrasensitive hybridization capture: Reliable detection of &lt;1 copy/mL short cell-free DNA from large-volume urine samples</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247851" title="Ultrasensitive hybridization capture: Reliable detection of &lt;1 copy/mL short cell-free DNA from large-volume urine samples" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247851.PDF" title="(PDF) Ultrasensitive hybridization capture: Reliable detection of &lt;1 copy/mL short cell-free DNA from large-volume urine samples" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247851.XML" title="(XML) Ultrasensitive hybridization capture: Reliable detection of &lt;1 copy/mL short cell-free DNA from large-volume urine samples" />
    <author>
      <name>Amy Oreskovic</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Barry R. Lutz</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247851</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Amy Oreskovic, Barry R. Lutz&lt;/p&gt;

Urine cell-free DNA (cfDNA) is a valuable non-invasive biomarker with broad potential clinical applications, but there is no consensus on its optimal pre-analytical methodology, including the DNA extraction step. Due to its short length (majority of fragments &lt;100 bp) and low concentration (ng/mL), urine cfDNA is not efficiently recovered by conventional silica-based extraction methods. To maximize sensitivity of urine cfDNA assays, we developed an ultrasensitive hybridization method that uses sequence-specific oligonucleotide capture probes immobilized on magnetic beads to improve extraction of short cfDNA from large-volume urine samples. Our hybridization method recovers near 100% (95% CI: 82.6–117.6%) of target-specific DNA from 10 mL urine, independent of fragment length (25–150 bp), and has a limit of detection of ≤5 copies of double-stranded DNA (0.5 copies/mL). Pairing hybridization with an ultrashort qPCR design, we can efficiently capture and amplify fragments as short as 25 bp. Our method enables amplification of cfDNA from 10 mL urine in a single qPCR well, tolerates variation in sample composition, and effectively removes non-target DNA. Our hybridization protocol improves upon both existing silica-based urine cfDNA extraction methods and previous hybridization-based sample preparation protocols. Two key innovations contribute to the strong performance of our method: a two-probe system enabling recovery of both strands of double-stranded DNA and dual biotinylated capture probes, which ensure consistent, high recovery by facilitating optimal probe density on the bead surface, improving thermostability of the probe-bead linkage, and eliminating interference by endogenous biotin. We originally designed the hybridization method for tuberculosis diagnosis from urine cfDNA, but expect that it will be versatile across urine cfDNA targets, and may be useful for other cfDNA sample types and applications beyond cfDNA. To make our hybridization method accessible to new users, we present a detailed protocol and straightforward guidelines for designing new capture probes.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Risk factors and true prevalence of bovine tuberculosis in Bangladesh</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247838" title="Risk factors and true prevalence of bovine tuberculosis in Bangladesh" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247838.PDF" title="(PDF) Risk factors and true prevalence of bovine tuberculosis in Bangladesh" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247838.XML" title="(XML) Risk factors and true prevalence of bovine tuberculosis in Bangladesh" />
    <author>
      <name>Md. Nazimul Islam</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mohammad Kamruzzaman Khan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mohammad Ferdousur Rahman Khan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Polychronis Kostoulas</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. K. M. Anisur Rahman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Md. Mahbub Alam</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247838</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Md. Nazimul Islam, Mohammad Kamruzzaman Khan, Mohammad Ferdousur Rahman Khan, Polychronis Kostoulas, A. K. M. Anisur Rahman, Md. Mahbub Alam&lt;/p&gt;

Bovine tuberculosis (bTb) is endemic in Bangladesh but the true prevalence has not yet been reported. Our objectives for this study were to determine the true prevalence and identify risk factors for bTb at the animal- and herd-level in Bangladesh. A total of 510 cows were randomly selected during January 2018 to December 2018. Caudal fold (CFT) and comparative cervical tuberculin tests (CCT) were serially interpreted. Animal- and herd-level risk factor data were collected using a pre-tested questionnaire. The hierarchical true prevalence of bTb was estimated within a Bayesian framework. The herd- and animal-level risk factors were identified using mixed effects logistic regression. The apparent prevalence of bTb was 20.6% [95% Confidence Interval (CI): 17.3; 24.3] based on CFT. The animal-level true prevalence of bTb was 21.9 (13.0; 32.4). The herd-level true prevalence in different regions varied from 41.9% to 88.8%. The region-level true prevalence was 49.9 (13.8; 91.2). There is a 100% certainty that herds from Bhaluka and Mymensingh Sadar upazilas are not free from bTb. The odds of bTb were 3.9 times (1.2; 12.6) higher in herds having more than four cows than those with ≤ 4 cows. On the other hand, the risk of bTb was 3.3 times higher (1.0; 10.5) in non-grazing cows than grazing cows. Crossbred cows were 2.9 times (1.5; 5.9) more likely to be infected with bTb than indigenous cows. The risk of bTb in animals with cough was 2.3 times (1.2; 4.3) higher than those without cough. Crossbred, non-grazing cows with cough should be targeted for bTb surveillance. Herds of the Mymensingh, Sadar and Bhaluka regions should be emphasized for bTb control programs. Estimation of Bayesian hierarchical true prevalence facilitates identification of areas with higher prevalence and can be used to indicate regions that where true prevalence exceeds a pre-specified critical threshold.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Altered immunoglobulin G glycosylation in patients with isolated hyperprolactinaemia</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247805" title="Altered immunoglobulin G glycosylation in patients with isolated hyperprolactinaemia" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247805.PDF" title="(PDF) Altered immunoglobulin G glycosylation in patients with isolated hyperprolactinaemia" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247805.XML" title="(XML) Altered immunoglobulin G glycosylation in patients with isolated hyperprolactinaemia" />
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Hirschberg</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bertil Ekman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jeanette Wahlberg</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eva Landberg</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247805</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Daniel Hirschberg, Bertil Ekman, Jeanette Wahlberg, Eva Landberg&lt;/p&gt;

Prolactin is a peptide hormone produced in the anterior pituitary, which increase in several physiological and pathological situations. It is unclear if hyperprolactinaemia may affect glycosylation of immunoglobulin G (IgG). Twenty-five patients with hyperprolactinemia and 22 healthy control subjects were included in the study. The groups had similar age and gender distribution. A panel of hormonal and haematological analyses, creatinine, glucose, liver enzymes and immunoglobulins were measured by routine clinical methods. IgG was purified from serum by Protein G Sepharose. Sialic acid was released from IgG by use of neuraminidase followed by quantification on high performance anion-exchange chromatography with pulsed amperometric detection. Tryptic glycopeptides of IgG was analysed by matrix-assisted laser desorption/ionization-time of flight mass spectrometry. Hormone and immunoglobulin levels were similar in the two groups, except for IgA and prolactin. Significantly higher IgG1 and IgG2/3 galactosylation was found in the patient group with hyperprolactinaemia compared to controls. (A significant correlation between prolactin and IgG2/3 galactosylation (Rs 0.61, p&lt;0.001) was found for samples with prolactin values below 2000 mIU/L. The relative amount of sialylated and bisecting glycans on IgG did not differ between patients and controls. The four macroprolactinaemic patients showed decreased relative amount of bisecting IgG2/3 glycans. Hyperprolactinaemia was found to be associated with increased galactosylation of IgG1and IgG2/3. This may have impact on IgG interactions with Fc-receptors, complement and lectins, and consequently lead to an altered immune response.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Myocardial injury in hospitalized patients with COVID-19 infection—Risk factors and outcomes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247800" title="Myocardial injury in hospitalized patients with COVID-19 infection—Risk factors and outcomes" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247800.PDF" title="(PDF) Myocardial injury in hospitalized patients with COVID-19 infection—Risk factors and outcomes" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247800.XML" title="(XML) Myocardial injury in hospitalized patients with COVID-19 infection—Risk factors and outcomes" />
    <author>
      <name>Orly Efros</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Noam Barda</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eshcar Meisel</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Avshalom Leibowitz</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alexander Fardman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Galia Rahav</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Klempfner</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ehud Grossman</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247800</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Orly Efros, Noam Barda, Eshcar Meisel, Avshalom Leibowitz, Alexander Fardman, Galia Rahav, Robert Klempfner, Ehud Grossman&lt;/p&gt;

Myocardial injury in hospitalized patients is associated with poor prognosis. This study aimed to evaluate risk factors for myocardial injury in hospitalized patients with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) and its prognostic value. We retrieved all consecutive patients who were hospitalized in internal medicine departments in a tertiary medical center from February 9&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, 2020 to August 28&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; with a diagnosis of COVID-19. A total of 559 adult patients were hospitalized in the Sheba Medical Center with a diagnosis of COVID-19, 320 (57.24%) of whom were tested for troponin levels within 24-hours of admission, and 91 (28.44%) had elevated levels. Predictors for elevated troponin levels were age (odds ratio [OR], 1.04; 95% confidence interval [CI], 1.01–1.06), female sex (OR, 3.03; 95% CI 1.54–6.25), low systolic blood pressure (OR, 5.91; 95% CI 2.42–14.44) and increased creatinine level (OR, 2.88; 95% CI 1.44–5.73). The risk for death (hazard ratio [HR] 4.32, 95% CI 2.08–8.99) and a composite outcome of invasive ventilation support and death (HR 1.96, 95% CI 1.15–3.37) was significantly higher among patients who had elevated troponin levels. In conclusion, in hospitalized patients with COVID-19, elevated troponin levels are associated with poor prognosis. Hence, troponin levels may be used as an additional tool for risk stratification and a decision guide in patients hospitalized with COVID-19.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Extraction-free protocol combining proteinase K and heat inactivation for detection of SARS-CoV-2 by RT-qPCR</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247792" title="Extraction-free protocol combining proteinase K and heat inactivation for detection of SARS-CoV-2 by RT-qPCR" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247792.PDF" title="(PDF) Extraction-free protocol combining proteinase K and heat inactivation for detection of SARS-CoV-2 by RT-qPCR" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247792.XML" title="(XML) Extraction-free protocol combining proteinase K and heat inactivation for detection of SARS-CoV-2 by RT-qPCR" />
    <author>
      <name>Valeria Genoud</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Martin Stortz</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ariel Waisman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bruno G. Berardino</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Paula Verneri</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Virginia Dansey</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Melina Salvatori</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Federico Remes Lenicov</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Valeria Levi</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247792</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Valeria Genoud, Martin Stortz, Ariel Waisman, Bruno G. Berardino, Paula Verneri, Virginia Dansey, Melina Salvatori, Federico Remes Lenicov, Valeria Levi&lt;/p&gt;

Real-time reverse transcription PCR (RT-qPCR) is the gold-standard technique for severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) detection in nasopharyngeal swabs specimens. The analysis by RT-qPCR usually requires a previous extraction step to obtain the purified viral RNA. Unfortunately, RNA extraction constitutes a bottleneck for early detection in many countries since it is expensive, time-consuming and depends on the availability of commercial kits. Here, we describe an extraction-free protocol for SARS-CoV-2 detection by RT-qPCR from nasopharyngeal swab clinical samples in saline solution. The method includes a treatment with proteinase K followed by heat inactivation (PK+HID method). We demonstrate that PK+HID improves the RT-qPCR performance in comparison to the heat-inactivation procedure. Moreover, we show that this extraction-free protocol can be combined with a variety of multiplexing RT-qPCR kits. The method combined with a multiplexing detection kit targeting N and ORF1ab viral genes showed a sensitivity of 0.99 and a specificity of 0.99 from the analysis of 106 positive and 106 negative clinical samples. In conclusion, PK+HID is a robust, fast and inexpensive procedure for extraction-free RT-qPCR determinations of SARS-CoV-2. The National Administration of Drugs, Foods and Medical Devices of Argentina has recently authorized the use of this method.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Transcriptome analysis of the role of autophagy in plant response to heat stress</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247783" title="Transcriptome analysis of the role of autophagy in plant response to heat stress" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247783.PDF" title="(PDF) Transcriptome analysis of the role of autophagy in plant response to heat stress" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247783.XML" title="(XML) Transcriptome analysis of the role of autophagy in plant response to heat stress" />
    <author>
      <name>Yan Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Haoxuan Min</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chengchen Shi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gengshou Xia</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhibing Lai</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247783</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Yan Zhang, Haoxuan Min, Chengchen Shi, Gengshou Xia, Zhibing Lai&lt;/p&gt;

Autophagy plays a critical role in plant heat tolerance in part by targeting heat-induced nonnative proteins for degradation. Autophagy also regulates metabolism, signaling and other processes and it is less understood how the broad function of autophagy affects plant heat stress responses. To address this issue, we performed transcriptome profiling of Arabidopsis wild-type and autophagy-deficient &lt;i&gt;atg5&lt;/i&gt; mutant in response to heat stress. A large number of differentially expressed genes (DEGs) were identified between wild-type and &lt;i&gt;atg5&lt;/i&gt; mutant even under normal conditions. These DEGs are involved not only in metabolism, hormone signaling, stress responses but also in regulation of nucleotide processing and DNA repair. Intriguingly, we found that heat treatment resulted in more robust changes in gene expression in wild-type than in the &lt;i&gt;atg5&lt;/i&gt; mutant plants. The dampening effect of autophagy deficiency on heat-regulated gene expression was associated with already altered expression of many heat-regulated DEGs prior to heat stress in the &lt;i&gt;atg5&lt;/i&gt; mutant. Altered expression of a large number of genes involved in metabolism and signaling in the autophagy mutant prior to heat stress may affect plant response to heat stress. Furthermore, autophagy played a positive role in the expression of defense- and stress-related genes during the early stage of heat stress responses but had little effect on heat-induced expression of heat shock genes. Taken together, these results indicate that the broad role of autophagy in metabolism, cellular homeostasis and other processes can also potentially affect plant heat stress responses and heat tolerance.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mitochondrial, lysosomal and DNA damages induced by acrylamide attenuate by ellagic acid in human lymphocyte</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247776" title="Mitochondrial, lysosomal and DNA damages induced by acrylamide attenuate by ellagic acid in human lymphocyte" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247776.PDF" title="(PDF) Mitochondrial, lysosomal and DNA damages induced by acrylamide attenuate by ellagic acid in human lymphocyte" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247776.XML" title="(XML) Mitochondrial, lysosomal and DNA damages induced by acrylamide attenuate by ellagic acid in human lymphocyte" />
    <author>
      <name>Ahmad Salimi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Elahe Baghal</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hassan Ghobadi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Niloufar Hashemidanesh</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Farzad Khodaparast</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Enayatollah Seydi</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247776</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Ahmad Salimi, Elahe Baghal, Hassan Ghobadi, Niloufar Hashemidanesh, Farzad Khodaparast, Enayatollah Seydi&lt;/p&gt;

Acrylamide (AA), is an important contaminant formed during food processing under high temperature. Due to its potential neurotoxicity, reproductive toxicity, hepatotoxicity, immunotoxicity, genotoxicity and carcinogenicity effects, this food contaminant has been recognized as a human health concern. Previous studies showed that acrylamide-induced toxicity is associated with active metabolite of acrylamide by cytochrome P450 enzyme, oxidative stress, mitochondrial dysfunction and DNA damage. In the current study, we investigated the role of oxidative stress in acrylamide’s genotoxicity and therapeutic potential role of ellagic acid (EA) in human lymphocytes. Human lymphocytes were simultaneously treated with different concentrations of EA (10, 25 and 50 μM) and acrylamide (50 μM) for 4 h at 37°C. After 4 hours of incubation, the toxicity parameters such cytotoxicity, ROS formation, oxidized/reduced glutathione (GSH/GSSG) content, malondialdehyde (MDA) level, lysosomal membrane integrity, mitochondria membrane potential (ΔΨm) collapse and 8-hydroxy-2’-deoxyguanosine (8-OHdG) were analyzed using biochemical and flow cytometry evaluations. It has been found that acrylamide (50 μM) significantly increased cytotoxicity, ROS formation, GSH oxidation, lipid peroxidation, MMP collapse, lysosomal and DNA damage in human lymphocytes. On the other hand, cotreatment with EA (25 and 50 μM) inhibited AA-induced oxidative stress which subsequently led to decreasing of the cytotoxicity, GSH oxidation, lipid peroxidation, MMP collapse, lysosomal and DNA damage. Together, these results suggest that probably the co-exposure of EA with foods containing acrylamide could decrease mitochondrial, lysosomal and DNA damages, and oxidative stress induced by acrylamide in human body.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Evaluation of sample pooling for screening of SARS CoV-2</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247767" title="Evaluation of sample pooling for screening of SARS CoV-2" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247767.PDF" title="(PDF) Evaluation of sample pooling for screening of SARS CoV-2" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247767.XML" title="(XML) Evaluation of sample pooling for screening of SARS CoV-2" />
    <author>
      <name>Andargachew Mulu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dawit Hailu Alemayehu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Fekadu Alemu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dessalegn Abeje Tefera</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sinknesh Wolde</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gebeyehu Aseffa</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tamrayehu Seyoum</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Meseret Habtamu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alemseged Abdissa</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Abebe Genetu Bayih</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Getachew Tesfaye Beyene</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247767</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Andargachew Mulu, Dawit Hailu Alemayehu, Fekadu Alemu, Dessalegn Abeje Tefera, Sinknesh Wolde, Gebeyehu Aseffa, Tamrayehu Seyoum, Meseret Habtamu, Alemseged Abdissa, Abebe Genetu Bayih, Getachew Tesfaye Beyene&lt;/p&gt;
Background &lt;p&gt;The coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic has revealed the global public health importance of robust diagnostic testing. To overcome the challenge of nucleic acid (NA) extraction and testing kit availability, an efficient method is urgently needed.&lt;/p&gt; Objectives &lt;p&gt;To establish an efficient, time and resource-saving and cost-effective methods, and to propose an &lt;i&gt;ad hoc&lt;/i&gt; pooling approach for mass screening of SARS-CoV-2.&lt;/p&gt; Methods &lt;p&gt;We evaluated pooling approach on both direct clinical and NA samples. The standard reverse transcriptase polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) test of the SARS CoV-2 was employed targeting the nucleocapsid (N) and open reading frame (ORF1ab) genomic region of the virus. The experimental pools were created using SARS CoV-2 positive clinical samples and extracted RNA spiked with up to 9 negative samples. For the direct clinical samples viral NA was extracted from each pool to a final extraction volume of 200μL, and subsequently both samples tested using the SARS CoV-2 RT-PCR assay.&lt;/p&gt; Results &lt;p&gt;We found that a single positive sample can be amplified and detected in pools of up to 7 samples depending on the cycle threshold (Ct) value of the original sample, corresponding to high, and low SARS CoV-2 viral copies per reaction. However, to minimize false negativity of the assay with pooling strategies and with unknown false negativity rate of the assay under validation, we recommend pooling of 4/5 in 1 using the standard protocols of the assay, reagents and equipment. The predictive algorithm indicated a pooling ratio of 5 in 1 was expected to retain accuracy of the test irrespective of the Ct value samples spiked, and result in a 137% increase in testing efficiency.&lt;/p&gt; Conclusions &lt;p&gt;The approaches showed its concept in easily customized and resource-saving manner and would allow expanding of current screening capacities and enable the expansion of detection in the community. We recommend clinical sample pooling of 4 or 5 in 1. However, we don’t advise pooling of clinical samples when disease prevalence is greater than 7%; particularly when sample size is large.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Causal relationship between the timing of menarche and young adult body mass index with consideration to a trend of consistently decreasing age at menarche</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247757" title="Causal relationship between the timing of menarche and young adult body mass index with consideration to a trend of consistently decreasing age at menarche" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247757.PDF" title="(PDF) Causal relationship between the timing of menarche and young adult body mass index with consideration to a trend of consistently decreasing age at menarche" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247757.XML" title="(XML) Causal relationship between the timing of menarche and young adult body mass index with consideration to a trend of consistently decreasing age at menarche" />
    <author>
      <name>Hakyung Kim</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Seung-Ah Choe</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Soo Ji Lee</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Joohon Sung</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247757</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Hakyung Kim, Seung-Ah Choe, Soo Ji Lee, Joohon Sung&lt;/p&gt;

Younger age at menarche (AAM) is associated with higher body mass index (BMI) for young women. Considering that continuous trends in decreasing AAM and increasing BMI are found in many countries, we attempted to assess whether the observed negative association between AAM and young adult BMI is causal. We included 4,093 women from the Korean Genome and Epidemiology Study (KoGES) and Healthy twin Study (HTS) with relevant epidemiologic data and genome-wide marker information. To mitigate the remarkable differences in AAM across generations, we converted the AAM to a generation-standardized AAM (gsAAM). To test causality, we applied the Mendelian randomization (MR) approach, using a genetic risk score (GRS) based on 14 AAM-associated single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs). We constructed MR models adjusting for education level and validated the results using the inverse-variance weighted (IVW), weighted median (WM), MR-pleiotropy residual sum and outliers test (MR-PRESSO), and MR-Egger regression methods. We found a null association using observed AAM and BMI level (conventional regression; -0.05 [95% CIs -0.10–0.00] per 1-year higher AAM). This null association was replicated when gsAAM was applied instead of AAM. Using the two-stage least squares (2SLS) approach employing a univariate GRS, the association was also negated for both AAM and gsAAM, regardless of model specifications. All the MR diagnostics suggested statistically insignificant associations, but weakly negative trends, without evidence of confounding from pleiotropy. We did not observe a causal association between AAM and young adult BMI whether we considered the birth cohort effect or not. Our study alone does not exclude the possibility of existing a weak negative association, considering the modest power of our study design.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Retrospective study of late radiation-induced damages after focal radiotherapy for childhood brain tumors</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247748" title="Retrospective study of late radiation-induced damages after focal radiotherapy for childhood brain tumors" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247748.PDF" title="(PDF) Retrospective study of late radiation-induced damages after focal radiotherapy for childhood brain tumors" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247748.XML" title="(XML) Retrospective study of late radiation-induced damages after focal radiotherapy for childhood brain tumors" />
    <author>
      <name>Claudia Cavatorta</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Silvia Meroni</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eros Montin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Maria C. Oprandi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Emilia Pecori</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mara Lecchi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Diletto</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ombretta Alessandro</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Denis Peruzzo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Veronica Biassoni</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabetta Schiavello</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marco Bologna</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Maura Massimino</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Geraldina Poggi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Luca Mainardi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Filippo Arrigoni</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Filippo Spreafico</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Paolo Verderio</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Emanuele Pignoli</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lorenza Gandola</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247748</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Claudia Cavatorta, Silvia Meroni, Eros Montin, Maria C. Oprandi, Emilia Pecori, Mara Lecchi, Barbara Diletto, Ombretta Alessandro, Denis Peruzzo, Veronica Biassoni, Elisabetta Schiavello, Marco Bologna, Maura Massimino, Geraldina Poggi, Luca Mainardi, Filippo Arrigoni, Filippo Spreafico, Paolo Verderio, Emanuele Pignoli, Lorenza Gandola&lt;/p&gt;
Purpose &lt;p&gt;To study a robust and reproducible procedure to investigate a relation between focal brain radiotherapy (RT) low doses, neurocognitive impairment and late White Matter and Gray Matter alterations, as shown by Diffusion Tensor Imaging (DTI), in children.&lt;/p&gt; Methods and materials &lt;p&gt;Forty-five patients (23 males and 22 females, median age at RT 6.2 years, median age at evaluations 11.1 years) who had received focal RT for brain tumors were recruited for DTI exams and neurocognitive tests. Patients’ brains were parceled in 116 regions of interest (ROIs) using an available segmented atlas. After the development of an ad hoc, home-made, multimodal and highly deformable registration framework, we collected mean RT doses and DTI metrics values for each ROI. The pattern of association between cognitive scores or domains and dose or DTI values was assessed in each ROI through both considering and excluding ROIs with mean doses higher than 75% of the prescription. Subsequently, a preliminary threshold value of dose discriminating patients with and without neurocognitive impairment was selected for the most relevant associations.&lt;/p&gt; Results &lt;p&gt;The workflow allowed us to identify 10 ROIs where RT dose and DTI metrics were significantly associated with cognitive tests results (p&lt;0.05). In 5/10 ROIs, RT dose and cognitive tests were associated with p&lt;0.01 and preliminary RT threshold dose values, implying a possible cognitive or neuropsychological damage, were calculated. The analysis of domains showed that the most involved one was the “school-related activities”.&lt;/p&gt; Conclusion &lt;p&gt;This analysis, despite being conducted on a retrospective cohort of children, shows that the identification of critical brain structures and respective radiation dose thresholds is achievable by combining, with appropriate methodological tools, the large amount of data arising from different sources. This supported the design of a prospective study to gain stronger evidence.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Fluoride release from two types of fluoride-containing orthodontic adhesives: Conventional versus resin-modified glass ionomer cements—An in vitro study</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247716" title="Fluoride release from two types of fluoride-containing orthodontic adhesives: Conventional versus resin-modified glass ionomer cements—An in vitro study" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247716.PDF" title="(PDF) Fluoride release from two types of fluoride-containing orthodontic adhesives: Conventional versus resin-modified glass ionomer cements—An in vitro study" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247716.XML" title="(XML) Fluoride release from two types of fluoride-containing orthodontic adhesives: Conventional versus resin-modified glass ionomer cements—An in vitro study" />
    <author>
      <name>Yasemin Dziuk</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sachin Chhatwani</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stephan C. Möhlhenrich</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sabrina Tulka</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ella A. Naumova</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gholamreza Danesh</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247716</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Yasemin Dziuk, Sachin Chhatwani, Stephan C. Möhlhenrich, Sabrina Tulka, Ella A. Naumova, Gholamreza Danesh&lt;/p&gt;
Introduction &lt;p&gt;Development of white spot lesions (WSLs) during orthodontic treatment is a common risk factor. Fixation of the orthodontic appliances with glass ionomer cements could reduce the prevalence of WSL’s due to their fluoride release capacities. The purpose of this study was to evaluate differences of fluoride release properties from resin-modified and conventional glass ionomer cements (GICs).&lt;/p&gt; Methods &lt;p&gt;The resin-modified GICs Fuji ORTHO LC (GC Orthodontics), Meron Plus QM (VOCO), as well as the conventional GICs Fuji ORTHO (GC Orthodontics), Meron (VOCO) and Ketac Cem Easymix (3M ESPE) were tested in this study. The different types of GICs were applied to hydroxyapatite discs according to the manufacturer’s instructions and stored in a solution of TISAB III (Total Ionic Strength Adjustment Buffer III) and fluoride-free water at 37°C. Fluoride measurements were made after 5 minutes, 2 hours, 24 hours, 14 days, 28 days, 2 months, 3 months and 6 months. One factor analysis of variance (ANOVA) was used for the overall comparison of the cumulative fluoride release (from measurement times of 5 minutes to 6 months) between the different materials with the overall level of significance set to 0.05. Tukey’s post hoc test was used for post hoc pairwise comparisons in the cumulative fluoride release between the different materials.&lt;/p&gt; Results &lt;p&gt;The cumulative fluoride release (mean ± sd) in descending order was: Fuji ORTHO LC (221.7 ± 10.29 ppm), Fuji ORTHO (191.5 ± 15.03 ppm), Meron Plus QM (173.0 ± 5.89 ppm), Meron (161.3 ± 7.84 ppm) and Ketac Cem Easymix (154.6 ± 6.09 ppm) within 6 months. Analysis of variance detected a significant difference in the cumulative fluoride release between at least two of the materials (rounded p-value &lt; 0.001). Pairwise analysis with Tukey’s post hoc test showed a significant difference in the cumulative fluoride release for all the comparisons except M and MPQM (p = 0.061) and KCE and M (p = 0.517).&lt;/p&gt; Conclusion &lt;p&gt;Fluoride ions were released cumulatively over the entire test period for all products. When comparing the two products from the same company (Fuji ORTHO LC vs. Fuji ORTHO from GC Orthodontics Europe GmbH and Meron Plus QM vs. Meron from VOCO GmbH, Mannheim, Germany), it can be said that the resin-modified GICs have a higher release than conventional GICs. The highest individual fluoride release of all GICs was at 24 hours. A general statement, whether resin-modified or conventional GICs have a higher release of fluoride cannot be made.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Assessing civility at an academic health science center: Implications for employee satisfaction and well-being</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247715" title="Assessing civility at an academic health science center: Implications for employee satisfaction and well-being" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247715.PDF" title="(PDF) Assessing civility at an academic health science center: Implications for employee satisfaction and well-being" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247715.XML" title="(XML) Assessing civility at an academic health science center: Implications for employee satisfaction and well-being" />
    <author>
      <name>Lisa A. Campbell</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jenna R. LaFreniere</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mhd Hasan Almekdash</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>David D. Perlmutter</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Huaxin Song</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Patricia J. Kelly</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rohali Keesari</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kay Leigh Shannon</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247715</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Lisa A. Campbell, Jenna R. LaFreniere, Mhd Hasan Almekdash, David D. Perlmutter, Huaxin Song, Patricia J. Kelly, Rohali Keesari, Kay Leigh Shannon&lt;/p&gt;

Incivilities are pervasive among workers in healthcare institutions. Previously identified effects include deterioration of employee physical and mental health, absenteeism, burnout, and turnover, as well as reduced patient safety and quality of care. This study documented factors related to organizational civility at an academic health sciences center (AHSC) as the basis for future intervention work. We used a cross-sectional research design to conduct an online survey at four of five campuses of an AHSC. Using the Organizational Civility Scale (OCS), we assessed differences across gender, race (White and non-White) and job type (faculty or staff) in the eleven subscales (frequency of incivility, perceptions of organizational climate, existence of civility resources, importance of civility resources, feelings about current employment, employee satisfaction, sources of stress, coping strategies, overall levels of stress/coping ability, and overall civility rating). Significant gender differences were found in six of the eleven subscales: perception of organizational climate (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; .001), existence of civility resources (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = .001), importance of civility resources (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; .001), frequency of incivilities (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; .001), employee satisfaction (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = .002), and overall civility rating (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = .007). Significant differences between respondents by self-identified race were found only in one subscale: existence of civility resources (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = .048). Significant differences were found between faculty and staff in four subscales: perception of organizational climate (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = .001), importance of civility resources (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = .02), employee satisfaction (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = .01), and overall levels of stress (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = .03). Results suggest that gender and employment type differences exist in the perception of organizational climate at the academic health center, while significant racial differences only occurred in reference to reported existence of civility resources. Attention to these differences should be incorporated into the development of programs to address the problem.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Self-focused attention and safety behaviours maintain social anxiety in adolescents: An experimental study</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247703" title="Self-focused attention and safety behaviours maintain social anxiety in adolescents: An experimental study" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247703.PDF" title="(PDF) Self-focused attention and safety behaviours maintain social anxiety in adolescents: An experimental study" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247703.XML" title="(XML) Self-focused attention and safety behaviours maintain social anxiety in adolescents: An experimental study" />
    <author>
      <name>Eleanor Leigh</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kenny Chiu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>David M. Clark</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247703</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Eleanor Leigh, Kenny Chiu, David M. Clark&lt;/p&gt;
Background &lt;p&gt;Self-focused attention and safety behaviours are both associated with adolescent social anxiety. In adults, experimental studies have indicated that the processes are causally implicated in social anxiety, but this hypothesis has not yet been tested in a youth sample.&lt;/p&gt; Methods &lt;p&gt;This experiment explored this possibility by asking high and low socially anxious adolescents (N = 57) to undertake conversations under different conditions. During one conversation they were instructed to focus on themselves and use safety behaviours, and in the other they focused externally and did not use safety behaviours. Self-report, conversation partner report and independent assessor ratings were taken.&lt;/p&gt; Results &lt;p&gt;Self-focus and safety behaviours increased feelings and appearance of anxiety and undermined performance for all participants, but only high socially anxious participants reported habitually using self-focus and safety behaviours.&lt;/p&gt; Conclusions &lt;p&gt;The findings provide support for the causal role of self-focus and safety behaviours in adolescent social anxiety and point to the potential clinical value of techniques reversing them to treat the disorder.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Evaluation of a real-time optoelectronic method in the diagnostics of CIN over four years of observations</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247702" title="Evaluation of a real-time optoelectronic method in the diagnostics of CIN over four years of observations" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247702.PDF" title="(PDF) Evaluation of a real-time optoelectronic method in the diagnostics of CIN over four years of observations" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247702.XML" title="(XML) Evaluation of a real-time optoelectronic method in the diagnostics of CIN over four years of observations" />
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Suchońska</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wanda Gajzlerska-Majewska</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mirosław Wielgoś</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247702</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Barbara Suchońska, Wanda Gajzlerska-Majewska, Mirosław Wielgoś&lt;/p&gt;

Cervical cancer is considered to be particularly amenable to prevention and highly treatable in its early stages. The real-time optoelectronic method of cervix examination seemed to be very promising in the detection of cervical squamous intraepithelial lesions and demonstrated relatively good efficacy. Although this method was introduced into clinics almost 10 years ago, it has not found its place in diagnostic schemes. At the moment, cytological smears and HPV detection with genotyping are still essential. TruScreen seems to be a slightly forgotten test. The aim of the study was to evaluate the efficacy and accuracy of TruScreen in detecting cervical pathology: CIN and cervical cancer confirmed with a histopathological diagnosis in comparison with other methods–cytology and colposcopy over four years of observations. The study was conducted on 130 women with abnormal Pap smear results. We can conclude that a real-time optoelectronic method like TruScreen can be useful as an effective initial cervical cancer screening in developing countries, possibly in combination with other methods. The combination of cytology and TruScreen examination may help clinicians to take decision about the next diagnostics steps (e.g. colposcopy) and contribute to better primary screening for cervical cancer.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cloning and high-level expression of monomeric human superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1) and its interaction with pyrimidine analogs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247684" title="Cloning and high-level expression of monomeric human superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1) and its interaction with pyrimidine analogs" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247684.PDF" title="(PDF) Cloning and high-level expression of monomeric human superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1) and its interaction with pyrimidine analogs" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247684.XML" title="(XML) Cloning and high-level expression of monomeric human superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1) and its interaction with pyrimidine analogs" />
    <author>
      <name>Marcia LeVatte</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Matthias Lipfert</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dipankar Roy</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Andriy Kovalenko</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>David Scott Wishart</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247684</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Marcia LeVatte, Matthias Lipfert, Dipankar Roy, Andriy Kovalenko, David Scott Wishart&lt;/p&gt;

Superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1) is known to be involved in the pathogenesis of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS) and is therefore considered to be an important ALS drug target. Identifying potential drug leads that bind to SOD1 and characterizing their interactions by nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) spectroscopy is complicated by the fact that SOD1 is a homodimer. Creating a monomeric version of SOD1 could alleviate these issues. A specially designed monomeric form of human superoxide dismutase (T2M4SOD1) was cloned into &lt;i&gt;E&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;i&gt;coli&lt;/i&gt; and its expression significantly enhanced using a number of novel DNA sequence, leader peptide and growth condition optimizations. Uniformly &lt;sup&gt;15&lt;/sup&gt;N-labeled T2M4SOD1 was prepared from minimal media using &lt;sup&gt;15&lt;/sup&gt;NH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;Cl as the &lt;sup&gt;15&lt;/sup&gt;N source. The T2M4SOD1 monomer (both &lt;sup&gt;15&lt;/sup&gt;N labeled and unlabeled) was correctly folded as confirmed by &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;H-NMR spectroscopy and active as confirmed by an in-gel enzymatic assay. To demonstrate the utility of this new SOD1 expression system for NMR-based drug screening, eight pyrimidine compounds were tested for binding to T2M4SOD1 by monitoring changes in their &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;H NMR and/or &lt;sup&gt;19&lt;/sup&gt;F-NMR spectra. Weak binding to 5-fluorouridine (FUrd) was observed via line broadening, but very minimal spectral changes were seen with uridine, 5-bromouridine or trifluridine. On the other hand, &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;H-NMR spectra of T2M4SOD1 with uracil or three halogenated derivatives of uracil changed dramatically suggesting that the pyrimidine moiety is the crucial binding component of FUrd. Interestingly, no change in tryptophan 32 (Trp32), the putative receptor for FUrd, was detected in the &lt;sup&gt;15&lt;/sup&gt;N-NMR spectra of &lt;sup&gt;15&lt;/sup&gt;N-T2M4SOD1 when mixed with these uracil analogs. Molecular docking and molecular dynamic (MD) studies indicate that interaction with Trp32 of SOD1 is predicted to be weak and that there was hydrogen bonding with the nearby aspartate (Asp96), potentiating the Trp32-uracil interaction. These studies demonstrate that monomeric T2M4SOD1 can be readily used to explore small molecule interactions via NMR.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Impella use in real-world cardiogenic shock patients: Sobering outcomes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247667" title="Impella use in real-world cardiogenic shock patients: Sobering outcomes" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247667.PDF" title="(PDF) Impella use in real-world cardiogenic shock patients: Sobering outcomes" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247667.XML" title="(XML) Impella use in real-world cardiogenic shock patients: Sobering outcomes" />
    <author>
      <name>Khaled Q. A. Abdullah</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jana V. Roedler</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Juergen vom Dahl</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Istvan Szendey</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hendrik Haake</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lars Eckardt</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Albert Topf</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bernhard Ohnewein</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Peter Jirak</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lukas J. Motloch</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bernhard Wernly</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Larbig</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247667</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Khaled Q. A. Abdullah, Jana V. Roedler, Juergen vom Dahl, Istvan Szendey, Hendrik Haake, Lars Eckardt, Albert Topf, Bernhard Ohnewein, Peter Jirak, Lukas J. Motloch, Bernhard Wernly, Robert Larbig&lt;/p&gt;
Background &lt;p&gt;Critically ill patients with cardiogenic shock could benefit from ventricular assist device support using the Impella microaxial blood pump. However, recent studies suggested Impella not to improve outcomes. We, therefore, evaluated outcomes and predictors in a real-world scenario.&lt;/p&gt; Methods &lt;p&gt;In this retrospective single-center trial, 125 patients suffering from cardiac arrest/cardiogenic shock between 2008 and 2018 were analyzed. 93 Patients had a prior successful cardiopulmonary resuscitation. The primary endpoint was hospital mortality. Associations of covariates with the primary endpoint were assessed by univariable and multivariable logistic regression. Adjusted odds ratios (aOR) and optimal cut-offs (using Youden index) were obtained.&lt;/p&gt; Results &lt;p&gt;Hospital mortality was high (81%). Baseline lactate was 4.7mmol/L [IQR = 7.1mmol/L]. In multivariable logistic regression, only age (aOR 1.13 95%CI 1.06–1.20; p&lt;0.001) and lactate (aOR 1.23 95%CI 1.004–1.516; p = 0.046) were associated with hospital mortality, and the respective optimal cut-offs were &gt;3.3mmol/L and age &gt;66 years.Patients were retrospectively stratified into three risk groups: Patients aged ≤66 years and lactate ≤3.3mmol (low-risk; n = 22); patients aged &gt;66 years or lactate &gt;3.3mmol/L (medium-risk; n = 52); and patients both aged &gt;66 years and lactate &gt;3.3mmol/L (high-risk, n = 51). Risk of death increased from 41% in the low-risk group, to 79% in the medium risk group and 100% in the high-risk group. The predictive abilities of this model were high (AUC 0.84; 95% 0.77–0.92).&lt;/p&gt; Conclusion &lt;p&gt;Mortality was high in this real-world collective of severely ill cardiogenic shock patients. Better patient selection is warranted to avoid unethical use of Impella. Age and lactate might help to improve patient selection.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cervical transcutaneous vagal neuromodulation in chronic pancreatitis patients with chronic pain: A randomised sham controlled clinical trial</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247653" title="Cervical transcutaneous vagal neuromodulation in chronic pancreatitis patients with chronic pain: A randomised sham controlled clinical trial" />
    <link rel="related" type="application/pdf" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247653.PDF" title="(PDF) Cervical transcutaneous vagal neuromodulation in chronic pancreatitis patients with chronic pain: A randomised sham controlled clinical trial" />
    <link rel="related" type="text/xml" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/asset?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0247653.XML" title="(XML) Cervical transcutaneous vagal neuromodulation in chronic pancreatitis patients with chronic pain: A randomised sham controlled clinical trial" />
    <author>
      <name>Janusiya Anajan Muthulingam</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Søren Schou Olesen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tine Maria Hansen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Brock</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Asbjørn Mohr Drewes</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jens Brøndum Frøkjær</name>
    </author>
    <id>10.1371/journal.pone.0247653</id>
    <updated>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-26T14:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;by Janusiya Anajan Muthulingam, Søren Schou Olesen, Tine Maria Hansen, Christina Brock, Asbjørn Mohr Drewes, Jens Brøndum Frøkjær&lt;/p&gt;
Background &amp; aims &lt;p&gt;Chronic abdominal pain is the primary symptom of chronic pancreatitis, but unfortunately it is difficult to treat. Vagal nerve stimulation studies have provided evidence of anti-nociceptive effect in several chronic pain conditions. We investigated the pain-relieving effects of transcutaneous vagal nerve stimulation in comparison to sham treatment in chronic pancreatitis patients.&lt;/p&gt; Methods &lt;p&gt;We conducted a randomised double-blinded, sham-controlled, crossover trial in patients with chronic pancreatitis. Patients were randomly assigned to receive a two-week period of cervical transcutaneous vagal nerve stimulation using the gammaCore device followed by a two-week sham stimulation, or vice versa. We measured clinical and experimental endpoints before and after each treatment. The primary clinical endpoint was pain relief, documented in a pain diary using a visual analogue scale. Secondary clinical endpoints included Patients’ Global Impression of Change score, quality of life and Brief Pain Inventory questionnaire. Secondary experimental endpoints included cardiac vagal tone and heart rate.&lt;/p&gt; Results &lt;p&gt;No differences in pain scores were seen in response to two weeks transcutaneous vagal nerve stimulation as compared to sham treatment (difference in average pain score (visual analogue scale): 0.17, 95%CI (-0.86;1.20), P = 0.7). Similarly, no differences were seen for secondary clinical endpoints, except from an increase in the appetite loss score (13.9, 95%CI (0.5:27.3), P = 0.04). However, improvements in maximum pain scores were seen for transcutaneous vagal nerve stimulation and sham treatments as compared to their respective baselines: vagal nerve stimulation (-1.3±1.7, 95%CI (-2.21:-0.42), P = 0.007), sham (-1.3±1.9, 95%CI (-2.28:-0.25), P = 0.018). Finally, heart rate was decreased after two weeks transcutaneous vagal nerve stimulation in comparison to sham treatment (-3.7 beats/min, 95%CI (-6.7:-0.6), P = 0.02).&lt;/p&gt; Conclusion &lt;p&gt;In this sham-controlled crossover study, we found no evidence that two weeks transcutaneous vagal nerve stimulation induces pain relief in patients with chronic pancreatitis.&lt;/p&gt; Trial registration number &lt;p&gt;The study is registered at NCT03357029; www.clinicaltrials.gov.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
